ROBERTFARLEY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Tulsa, OK 570-209-6717 rfarley@gmail.com

www.nomadrob.com | linkedin.com/in/robertfarley89 | github.com/Nomad-Rob

PROFILE SUMMARY

From leading a small unit in counter narcotic operations to flying helicopters. With a commitment to tackle new challenges, I've extended my expertise to modern web development, utilizing technologies to create clean projects and code. I'm dedicated to accelerating project success, analyzing complex issues, and Fullstack software engineering solutions that make a difference.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

| JavaScript | Bootstrap | Python | MySQL | Git/GitHub |
|------------|------------|---------|-------------|------------|
| ReactJS | HTML & CSS | Node.js | Linux/UNIX | JSON |
| jQuery | Docker | MongoDB | RESTful API | OOP |

PROJECTS

Holberton Hacksprint - Wes's Cozy Kitchen

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Hack_Sprint-Breakfast

- Developed a Python program utlizing Pygame library during a Hacksprint
- Primary role during project was Database and Game Logic

Technologies utilized - Python, Pygame, and JSON

Job Application Tracker

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/job_tracker

- Created a job tracker program that allows user to manage (CRUD) data from a database
- Created an intuitive search and filter system, enabling users to quickly locate specific job applications

Technologies utilized - JavaScript, MySQL, Docker, OOP, Python, HTML & CSS

AirBnB Clone

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/holbertonschool-AirBnB_clone_v4

- Developed a fully functional Airbnb clone web application from scratch, showcasing proficiency in full-stack web development
- Implemented user authentication, property listing, and booking functionalities, creating an interactive and user-friendly platform

Technologies utilized - Python, MySQL, ¡Query, Flask, JavaScript, JSON, HTML & CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oklahoma Army National Guard

2006-2023

- UH60M Helicopter Pilot 2020-Present
 - Proficient in diverse aircraft missions including Troop, Movement, Sling Loads, Assault,
 Water Buckets with hundreds of hours in the aircraft
 - Utilized skills such as Flight Planning, Pre-flight checks, Mentorship, Navigation, System Management, Emergency Procedures, and Monitor in-flight data

- Oklahoma Counterdrug Ground Recon Team Leader (2016-2019)
 - Led a 6-10 man unit in support of law enforcement with counter narcotic operations in rural and urban environments in Oklahoma in over 100 missions
 - o Utilized photography, audio, and video surveillance as well as infiltration techniques
 - Served as the subject matter expert for Oklahoma's Ground team in support of law enforcement with participation in over \$45,000,000 seized throughout my tenor
- Sniper/Scout Platoon Sergeant (2006–2020)
 - o Trained and led 32 soldiers in various training, combat operations, and mentorship
 - o Deployed multiple times, competed in International Joint Service Sniper competitions
 - Fostered Multi-National relationships with foreign entities

Aegis/GardaWorld Federal Services

Designated Defensive Marksman/Protective Security Specialist

2019-2020

- Performed protective security functions for key Department of State personnel while in Kabul Afghanistan
- Conducted pre site surveys on over 25 locations while in a high security posture or low visibility operations
- Successfully maintained over 95% qualifications on over 10 weapon systems quarterly

Xerox Business Solutions Southwest (Apple Contract) Senior Technical Advisor

2015-2016

- Managed a team of 20 or more personnel to successfully provide exceptional support and resolution to ongoing technical issues while maintaining certain metrics
- Directly coordinated with iOS and CPU engineers through help desk tickets to provide issue resolution with a 97% resolution rate

EDUCATION

Holberton Tulsa

Diploma - Computer Science & Full-Stack Web Development

Rigorous 20 month computer science and software engineering school that is project and peer-learning bases.

| () | н | - | ĸ |
|---------|---|---|----|
| \circ | | _ | ١, |

Commerical Aircraft Pilot (Helicopter)